<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

    <title>Eli Richmond's Blog</title>
    <link href="http://bloge.li/articles"/>
    <updated>2002-11-26T18:30:02Z</updated>
    <author>
    <name>Eli Richmond</name>
    </author>
    <id>bloge.li</id>
    <logo>https://bloge.li/static/xi.png</logo>
    <icon>https://bloge.li/static/xi.png</icon>

    
        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2023-07-26</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2023-07-26"/>
            <title>
                AI angst
            </title>
            <published>2023-07-26T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2></h2>
<p>
                AI is everywhere, and it is scary.
                Even the godfathers of AI like Yoshua Bengio and Geoffrey Hinton have expressed their anxiety.
                So no, you are not alone.
                However, recently I have found <i>some</i> peace with the whole thing.
                Maybe my thoughts will bring you some solace as well.
            </p><p>
                First of all I need to split this AI anxiety into two categories.
            </p><p>
                #1 is a fear of AI being evil or being used for evil.
                Here we are referring to the immortal dictator that enslaves humans or the normal dictators that could turn the world into George Orwell's 1984 by using this tech.
            </p><p>
                #2 is a fear of lost purpose.
                Here I'm referring to some existential questions that we must seriously consider.
                What does it even mean to be human in world where AI is smarter than everyone?
                How do we come to grips with the idea that we aren't special anymore?
                What do we do with ourselves when we don't have to work anymore?
                What do we do with ourselves when we are useless in comparison to our AI counterparts?
            </p><p>
                So what do I think?
            </p>
<h3>#1 Fear of evil</h3>
<p>
                This doesn't not give me any angst whatsoever.
                Okay maybe a little, but no more than any other new technology.
                We have always had to remain vigilant that new tech doesn't skew towards evil.
                Each new thing brings its own unique challenges, but this is simply a matter of courage.
                Let's buck up, do the work, and go boldly forward.
                In fact, I'm more afraid of stagnation than the potential evils of AI.
            </p>
<h3>#2 Fear of lost purpose</h3>
<p>
                I'm pretty sure we are just machines.
                I don't know this for a fact, and I'm not here to persuade anyone either.
                But the more these transformer language models - like chatGPT - advance, the more I feel like a simple biological machine without anything magical or special going on inside.
            </p><p> 
                If biological humans aren't all that special and we are both just machines, why be so anxious?
                They are just the next step up in machinery.
                AI isn't us, but we are the stepping stone that led to them.
                We would be arrogant and ignorant to assume we are the best possible version of ourselves.
                And I'm hopeful that they can be better than us.
                That is a good thing right?
                Being better?
                Why be so caught up with the idea that our specific configuration of flesh and bones must do the job?
            </p><p>
                ...
            </p><p>
                I do think it is a possibility that we could augment ourselves to remain useful.
                But here I'm considering the worse case scenario.
                Because if we can be at peace with the absolute worst case, anything less is manageable.
            </p><p>
                I'm sure my ideas on this topic will grow and change over time, but for now, this about covers it.
            </p><p>
                What are your thoughts?
                Is this helpful?
            </p>
<small>
                
            </small>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    

        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2023-07-20</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2023-07-20"/>
            <title>
                This feels (mostly) right
            </title>
            <published>2023-07-20T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2></h2>
<p>
                I wanted to document what my life is like during my time here at East Carolina University this summer for my REU program.
                The balance I've struck here has me feeling really good.
                So this could be useful to have in the future if I find myself feeling sub par.
                Maybe it could be helpful for you too.
            </p>
<h3>Work:</h3>
<p>
                We have a little less than a 40 hour work week.
                I'm working by myself on a project that I thought of and am implementing all on my own.
                It has been very fulfilling.
                I also don't feel like I'm working so much that other aspects of my life are being neglected which has not always been true with other forms of work.
            </p><p>
                I might could find a little more satisfaction if I were working on something with more future potential.
                I don't think I will take this research any further once I am done.
                So having something that could grow into my wildest dreams could make the work better.
                Working with a team could also be better.
                I'm in the room with everyone else during the week, but we are all doing our own thing.
                If my situation incorporated these two things, I could probably work many more hours each week and still maintain my health.
            </p>
<h3>Health:</h3>
<p>
                I'm getting 45 minutes worth of cardio/gym time about 5 days a week.
                Wednesday I attend an AI journal club where we read papers and Friday the gym closes too early for me to get there.
                For food I am getting about 2500 calories.
                Overall, I don't think my health is getting worse, and I don't feel bad.
                Earlier in the summer I tried to cut out sweets, but I found myself craving them late at night.
                This was very distracting.
                Now I usually have 2 or 3 chocolate chip cookies for lunch and that has helped.
            </p><p> 
                The only thing I would change here is getting better quality food.
                Subway and cafeteria food aren't a long term solution despite being my only options here.
            </p>
<h3>Friends:</h3>
<p>
                I generally hang out with people twice a week on Friday night and Saturday during the day.
                This has been the perfect amount for me.
                I still have plenty of me time, but knowing I will have something fun to do twice each weekend has been great.
                Having people that share many interests with me has also been fantastic.
                I love talking about AI, companies, computers, books, and other somewhat technical things and so do a lot of the people here.
            </p><p> 
                Having people so readily available to hang out during the week has been somewhat distracting though.
                There isn't much time in the day after we get out of work.
                And I like to spend it doing things for me.
                Some days I find myself wasting a bit more time than I'd like just hanging out.
            </p>
<h3>Housing:</h3>
<p>
                Living on my own has also been terrific.
                I do have a roommate.
                But we don't bother one another almost at all, which is good.
                It is always quiet - unlike home.
                I have almost no stuff with me and that is nice too.
                Our room has a patio outside the window.
                And given the perfect bug-less 75 degree temps, I love going out there to hang out on the roof.
            </p>
<small>
                
            </small>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    

        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2023-07-16</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2023-07-16"/>
            <title>
                You can change that
            </title>
            <published>2023-07-16T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2></h2>
<blockquote>
                "The mass of men lead lives of quiet desperation"
                <br/>
                - Henry David Thoreau
            </blockquote>
<p>
                This quote is referring to the people who are living empty lives due to unfulfilling work and too little freedom.
                However, nobody wakes up and says, "Ah yes. Today I'd like to find some meaningless work and a boss that won't let me go to the bathroom without pulling out a stopwatch."
                People never purposely decide to live poorly.
                So how do they fall into a life like this?
            </p><p>
                Have you ever been scrolling through a website on your phone and the text is way too big?
                You can change that.
                Have you ever been annoyed by the distracting ads and pop ups on every single page?
                You can change that.
                What about those websites that don't support dark mode and burn your eyeballs late at night?
                You can change that.
                Literally every single thing about your internet experience can be altered however you would like.
                Yet many people fuss with their phone in quiet desperation.
            </p><p>
                Often people live their lives the same way they interact with the internet.
                They take whatever situation the world hands them without question.
                Most of the time, the situation they are handed is purely random - a roll of the dice.
                If the odds put them in a tough position, so be it.
                Their job was an opportunity that just so happened to be available when they needed it.
                They never left their hometown because they just so happened to be born there.
                There are endless examples like this.
                Yet despite the ability to change everything, they don't.
            </p><p>
                We are the only thing in the known universe whose wants are unbounded.
                And almost anything we want, we can change.
                <b>Push, poke, prod, and will things into existence.
                It is our gift, and we should use it.</b>
</p>
<small>
                
            </small>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    

        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2023-07-9</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2023-07-9"/>
            <title>
                What is fulfilling work?
            </title>
            <published>2023-07-09T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2></h2>
<p>
                The perfect work requires four things.
            </p><p>
<i><b>#1 The product of this work must be beautiful as it can be - a true work of art.</b></i>
</p><p>
                This will require an extreme level of care in order to ensure the product is as beautiful and great as it can be in form, function, and the story it tells.
            </p><p>
                By the very nature of art, the product is a reflection of ourself, a reflection of our taste that has been slowly curated through every experience we have ever had.
                It is a product of our existence.
            </p><p>
                This doesn't just mean painting and music either.
                Art and beauty can be found in any medium.
            </p><p>
<i><b>#2 The work must require greatness from ourselves.</b></i>
</p><p>
                In the pursuit of the best product we can possibly make, the work should challenge us and push the limits of our abilities.
            </p><p>
<i><b>#3 The product of our work must be in service to other people.</b></i>
</p><p>
                Almost anything can be for others.
                Sharing the product of our work - thus ensuring it is in service - is a top priority.
            </p><p>
<i><b>#4 The work should be something we would do even if we never got paid or recognized for it.</b></i>
</p><p>
                Work worth doing, is work worth doing today.
            </p><p>
<br/>
<br/>
                So next time you are thinking about what you should do with your life, consider asking these questions.
            </p><p>
                Is this art to me, and do I care enough about this work to make it as beautiful and great as I possibly can?<br/>
                Is this work going to push the limits of what I'm capable of?<br/>
                Is this work going to serve others, and what do I need to do to ensure it can?<br/>
                Would I do this work even if I had all the money and attention I wanted, and if so, why not start today?<br/>
</p><p>
                ...
            </p><p>
                I used to think there was a fifth thing.
            </p><p>
<i><b>#5 The product of the work must be innovative.</b></i>
</p><p>
                My preferred medium is technology.
                And innovation and tech often walk hand in hand.
                However, I don't think innovation is essential to fulfilling work anymore.
            </p><p>
                ...
            </p><p>
                I'd like to start a company.
                As far as I know, it is the best way to work on technology.
                (My perfect work.)
                But how can I start a company if I'm not concerned with making innovative things?
            </p><p>
                I think pure taste is valuable enough to make a company successful.
                The brand, the story a company and its products tell is enough.
            </p>
<small>
                
            </small>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    

        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2023-07-2</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2023-07-2"/>
            <title>
                Crushing children's dreams
            </title>
            <published>2023-07-02T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2></h2>
<p>
                Some kids are dreamers.
                Though, on the road from childhood to adults, almost everyone stops dreaming.
            </p><p>
                We can probably all remember (or imagine) the first time we nervously shared a big dream with our parents, teachers, or another adult only to be scoffed at, not taken seriously, or told some watered down version of "You can't do that".
                It was a gut punch.
                It hurt.
                It was frustrating and unexpected.
                Who are they to make that call?
            </p><p>
                In my case, sometimes my parents and teachers were supportive with their words, but when it came time for them to step up, their actions didn't match.
                I didn't understand.
                I was angry.
                Sure the things I wanted to do were unusual, uncomfortable, and likely to fail, but that was the cost of admission.
                Why wouldn't my biggest supporters believe in me?
                I felt crazy.
            </p><p>
                This led me to believe modern education needed to be reformed and tailored to all the creative dreamers out there.
                They were the ones pushing everyone forward, so why are so many of their dreams getting crushed as children?
                It was wrong and needed to be fixed.
                Turns out, I was wrong.
                Nothing was broken in the first place.
            </p><p>
                We should replace Chief Executive Officer with Chief Executive Punching-bag.
                An entrepreneur's job title is to get told "No. You are crazy." over and over and over by potential investors, employees, and customers.
                Every single day feels like the gut punch from childhood.
                For most people, starting a company makes no sense.
                It requires enduring extreme pain for a very risky potential payoff.
                So why is anyone an entrepreneur?
            </p><p>
                Simple.
                <i>They can't live without it - they have no other choice.</i>
                True entrepreneurs are going to do what they do regardless of any advice or discouragement.
            </p><p>
                Dreaming of any kind is no different.
                It is hard.
                And seemingly the whole world is against the dream.
                For most people is it easier to stop dreaming than to pursue whatever it is.
                So they do.
                It doesn't take long either and is nobody's fault.
                There is nothing wrong with it.
                It was going to happen eventually.
                <i>They could live without it.</i>
</p><p>
                Of course I'm all for giving children endless love and support for their dreams.
                I would rather have people fail as adults than be discouraged as children.
                But in some cases, the world doesn't work that way, and it might be okay.
            </p><p>
                For those who <i>have no other choice</i> - I'm talking to you, dreamers - y'all will have to fight like hell every single day to keep that spark alive.
                But I'm excited for you.
                Keep dreaming - as if you even have a choice ;)
            </p>
<small>
                
            </small>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    

        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2023-06-20</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2023-06-20"/>
            <title>
                What do you like?
            </title>
            <published>2023-06-20T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2>
                What do <i>you</i> like?
            </h2>
<p>
                We all have so much potential.
                Many of my peers hide the best parts of themselves.
                It is a shame.
                Every once in a while, seemingly by accident, I'll catch a glimpse of who they really are.
                For a moment, they let their guard down.
                These small sparks of personality are beautiful.
                We all should do our best to find and share who we are.
            </p><p>
                It is time to leave our high school days of dogma, cliques, and following instructions behind.
                The real world celebrates individuality, uniqueness, obsession, breaking the rules, or making a new game entirely.
                Our own path is the only path.
                We won't find fulfillment or excitement by blending into the pack any longer.
            </p><p>
                Start by listening to yourself.
                Try being present and really attentive to how things and experiences make you feel.
                Paying attention is all it takes.
                Ever so slowly, we might find a little more of ourselves.
                Thus, we might have a little more to share - something real, something you.
            </p><p>
                When exposing our thoughts, feelings, and interests we leave the door open to be attacked.
                We also leave the door open to even deeper connections and love.
                It is worth the fear and discomfort.
                Be bold and share who you are.
            </p><p>
                Go.<br/>
                Listen.<br/>
                Pay attention.<br/>
                Feel.<br/>
                Be courageous.<br/>
                Share.<br/>
                Smile.<br/>
                Be you.<br/>
</p><p>
                If you know what you like, why is figuring out what you want so hard?
                Perhaps, you don't.
            </p>
<small>
                
            </small>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    

        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2023-06-10</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2023-06-10"/>
            <title>
                My creativity experiment
            </title>
            <published>2023-06-10T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2></h2>
<p>
                Every day during my spring semester I headed to The Den at 5:30am.
                If anyone asked, it was my office.
                But in reality it was a 10x10 storage unit I had rented out.
                Inside was a desk, a chair, and a small heater.
            </p><p>
                I wanted to explore what creativity was without any preconceived notions about it.
                For that I needed a quiet, consistent, and safe place to focus.
            </p><p>
                I didn't want any expectations as to how my hours would be spent each day.
                My only rule was that I couldn't distract myself.
                For example, sitting in silence and allowing my mind to wander was fine, but I couldn't watch YouTube or scroll through Instagram.
                Often I'd make music, write, program, draw, or use any creative medium that seemed interesting.
                I never had any plans or projects I had to finish.
                All I wanted to do was to put in my 3 hours of creativty and see what happens.
            </p><p>
                I feel like I learned a lot about myself, even though that is hard to quantify.
                Working with so many different mediums also taught me that all creative work feels the same day to day.
                Before I thought I could never be a musician because it wouldn't be intellectually stimulating enough compared to engineering.
                I was dead wrong.
                The grind of making music day to day is just as difficult and exciting.
            </p><p>
                However, the long term significance a project holds is different.
                Think about building rockets or making the next hit video game.
                The long term fulfillment of these two things will vary a lot between people - they carry different amounts of significance based on the person.
                But the day to day grind will feel very similar.
                Each will have similarly compelling problems to overcome on a short enough timescale.
            </p><p>
                This is important because we can get lost in the grind of someone else's mission.
                Day to day we might be stimulated and intrigued but over the long term we aren't pursuing what would bring us more fulfillment and satisfaction.
            </p><p>
                What could you contribute to the world over a 10 year period?
            </p>
<small>
                
            </small>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    

        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2023-05-28</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2023-05-28"/>
            <title>
                Crazy or courageous?
            </title>
            <published>2023-05-28T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2></h2>
<p>
                A few key moments will define us.
                I've noticed when I'm faced with these impactful decisions, there have been two choices: normal or crazy.
            </p><p>
                The crazy choice is almost always blatantly harder, requiring more work, consistency, and creativity.
                But also this route forces us to go against the grain of social convention.
                This causes friction with friends, family, bosses, committees, etc.
            </p><p>
                The crazy choice hurts so good.
                The pain is immense.
                But the satisfaction is too.
            </p><p>
                The crazy choice requires humility.
                It could be, well - crazy.
            </p><p>
                The crazy choice will reveal our friends.
                Some people won't stick around when we go our own way.
                But the relationships that hold up become stronger.
            </p><p>
                The crazy choice is scary/exciting.
                It requires us to put something on the line.
                We could publicly fail.
            </p><p>
                The crazy choice often minimizes regret.
                We can always be normal.
                The window for crazy can be fleeting.
            </p><p>
                The crazy choice might be the courageous choice.
                Most of the time choosing crazy has turned out great for me, far greater than the normal choice.
                Next time you are feeling a lot of opposition, consider that you might not be crazy.
                Maybe you are being courageous.
            </p><p>
                We need your courage.
            </p><p>
                ...
            </p><p>
                To my friends and family that have put up with my craziness over the years, Thank You :)
            </p>
<small>
                
            </small>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    

        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2023-05-21</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2023-05-21"/>
            <title>
                Taste is everything
            </title>
            <published>2023-05-21T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2></h2>
<p>
                Engineering or picking guitar strings used to be necessary and important.
                Today, all creative skills are quickly becoming irrelevant.
            </p><p>
                Before, there was no other way to bring new creative ideas to life.
                We had to have skill.
                But now AI can churn out an endless amount of paintings, stories, and soon - everything.
                Skills are quickly going away.
                Only our perspective is left.
                Our voice, our story, our filter, our taste.
                That is where the value lies.
            </p><p>
                Soon we all will be painters, musicians, writers, engineers, animators, film makers, game designers, and whatever else we wish to be - no skills required.
            </p><p>
                What will you build now that AI handles the execution?
                After all, your taste is everything.
            </p><p>
                ...
            </p><p>
                It will take more time for AI to catch up to some things.
                Running a business is a difficult creative task.
                But it will happen.
            </p><p>
                Maybe by that point AI will have its own taste.
                Maybe we will be competing with something we can't beat.
                Something we struggle to even understand.
            </p><p>
                I'm not sure what happens then.
                But I'm optimistic it will be beautiful.
            </p>
<small>
                
            </small>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    

        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2023-05-18</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2023-05-18"/>
            <title>
                Getting and choosing
            </title>
            <published>2023-05-18T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2></h2>
<p>
                Getting what you want is not the hard part.
                Choosing what you want is.
            </p><p>
                Because the more we get, the more we realize the cost of getting.
            </p><p>
                We might try making better choices but to no avail.
                One day, we might stop choosing.
                We might realize getting isn't worth it.
            </p><p>
                But we must choose something.
                Life forces it.
                This leads to frustration.
            </p><p>
                The only liberation is to continue strategically choosing until you don't have to anymore.
                At some point, we can find a place where we can, but don't need to, choose.
            </p><p>
                Sure, we will probably still choose.
                But the outcome of our choice no longer matters - internally or externally.
            </p><p>
                Being purposely dissconnected from getting and choosing is the ultimate freedom.
            </p>
<small>
                
            </small>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    

        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2023-05-17</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2023-05-17"/>
            <title>
                Dude face care
            </title>
            <published>2023-05-17T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2></h2>
<p>            
                Every night before you go to sleep grab a towel and soak a corner of it in cold water.
            </p><p>
                Gently wash your whole face.
            </p><p>
                You can't have too much or too cold of water.
                So it is better to overdo it.
            </p><p>
                That's all.
                Forget the expensive face washes and creams.
                Do this without skipping.
            </p><p>
                My face is considerably clearer.
            </p>
<small>
                
            </small>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    

        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2023-05-16</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2023-05-16"/>
            <title>
                Just make plans
            </title>
            <published>2023-05-16T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2></h2>
<p>            
                We are social creatures, no doubt about it.
                Friends are a biological necessity.
                But hanging out has its challenges.
            </p><p>    
                If we are thirsty, we can go get a drink.
                However, our friends aren't always free whenever we want (or perhaps need) them to be.
            </p><p>
                For too long I would deal with this uncomfortable feeling.
                If nobody was free, tough luck.
                I would feel bad and nothing productive would get done.
            </p><p>
                One day I called my friend.
                They were busy and couldn't hang out for whatever reason.
                Ugh.
                It was alright but disappointing for sure.
                They said, "Wanna make plans?"
                We did.
                I didn't think much about it.
                And a few minutes later I found myself in a really great mood.
                This caught me off guard.
            </p><p>
                All I had to do was make plans.
            </p><p>
                Knowing that I would see my friend in a few days quenched my thirst.
                It was enough.
            </p>
<small>
                
            </small>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    

        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2023-05-11</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2023-05-11"/>
            <title>
                Let your body decide
            </title>
            <published>2023-05-11T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2></h2>
<p>
                So you have a project idea in mind.
                It is exciting, but you don't know if it worth pursuing.
                Perhaps you have tried starting, but the work is awfully strenuous.
                Still, it has potential.
                Do you choose to keep looking or commit to this idea?
            </p><p>
                Maybe we should let our body decide for us.
            </p><p> 
                This might blow your mind, but we are not reasonable creatures.
                Over the long-term, we do what feels good.
                However, we can force ourselves to do things that don't feel good for a short period of time.
            </p><p>
                Before I get to the creative side of things, it helps to understand how habits are formed.
                Going to the gym is a great example.
            </p><p>
                When we first start exercising, it is a double whammy of suck.
                It sucks before we even get there.
                Just thinking about working out will make us feel like crap.
                And it definitely sucks while we are working out.
                Finally, if we make it through, we get a release of feel-good chemicals in our brain.
            </p><p>
                Training your body to do anything habitually takes time, but most habits - like eating sweets - don't take an immense amount of effort up-front, like exercising.
                That is why it is easy to form low effort habits.
                Eventually, our body starts to understand going through this pain period makes us feel great.
                Then exercise becomes just a single whammy of suck.
                It doesn't suck before you get there because your body isn't rebelling, it knows the good feeling will come later.
                Of course, the actual workout will always be hard.
                But getting there won't.
                Boom.
                Habit formed.
            </p><p>
                When wrestling with a project commitment try and form a habit of showing up first.
                Force yourself to work long enough for the potential to be there.
                The difference between this and starting to exercise is we don't know if this project can turn into a habit.
                We know working out makes us feel good.
                But despite whatever logical story we are telling ourselves, this creative project might not.
                If it doesn't, we won't be able to show up everyday.
                If it does, then we know that we can commit to this.
                Our body will decide whether or not the project is worthwhile.
            </p><p>
                There are still other factors to consider when committing to a project.
                But there have been many times where I thought I was in love with an idea; however, I couldn't get myself to habitually work on it.
                This allowed me to stop wrestling with the commitment question altogether.
            </p>
<small>
                
            </small>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    

        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2023-05-10</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2023-05-10"/>
            <title>
                Unnecessary confidentiality sucks
            </title>
            <published>2023-05-10T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2></h2>
<p>
                The downsides of confidentiality might not be considered as much as they should.
                When the people involved in a project can't talk about what they are working on, the secrecy causes inadvertent problems.
            </p><p>
                Government projects seem to hastily put shields up around their work.
                There can be good reasons for this but consider the cons.
            </p><p>
                When nobody can know what a project is, progress is only measured internally.
                This lack of outside accountability causes inefficiency to run wild.
                If the project funding is taxpayer money too, there is no significant financial risk either, only making things worse.
            </p><p>
                Since you can't tell your friends and family what you are doing, there is a lack of recognition.
                Also, since the leaders can't sell the public on this idea, the project won't be able to attract the best talent an otherwise open project would.
                Nothing kills our motivation to work like being overlooked and working with half-rate employees.
            </p><p>
                The ethical standards can start to degrade as well.
                Without information the public can't check the government's actions.
                Aside from an abuse of power, an environment where this is accepted will cause good hearted people to leave.
                Culture rot will slowly ensue.
            </p><p>
                I'm not informed enough to decide whether a project should be confidential or not.
                But have the conversation.
                Don't assume there are no downsides to unnecessary secrecy.
            </p>
<small>
                
            </small>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    

        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2023-05-8</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2023-05-8"/>
            <title>
                Give it all you've got
            </title>
            <published>2023-05-08T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2></h2>
<p>
                Great teams are beautiful.
                If you ever get the chance to be in a group working extremely hard towards a shared interest, please give it all you've got or leave.
            </p><p>
                This is one of the rarest experiences.
                We will only get a handful of these opportunities, if we are lucky.
            </p><p>
                Great teams are more capable than the sum of their parts.
                Extra care gets compounded in ways it normally wouldn't.
                However, lack of care compounds in the opposite direction.
            </p><p>
                We should consider caring deeply.
                Nobody lives too full a life.
                And when we choose not to care and not to leave, we are corroding something beautiful and fragile.
            </p><p>
                Nothing excites me more than these rare opportunities.
            </p>
<small>
                
            </small>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    

        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2023-04-27</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2023-04-27"/>
            <title>
                Living slowly
            </title>
            <published>2023-04-27T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2></h2>
<p>
<i>I enjoy living slowly.</i>
</p><p>
                This feels like: peace, contentment, mental clarity, empathy and care towards others, joy, calmness, patient ambition, confidence, curiosity.
            </p><p>
                Living fast feels like: anxiety, insufficiency, brain fog, unintentional selfishness, misdirection, hurry, restless ambition, insecurity, boredom.
            </p><p>
                The pace of my clock can be steadied by the things I do.
            </p><p>
                Some slow setting activities are: reading, writing, jogging, doing nothing, being alone, working on interesting things, focusing on one thing, silence.
            </p><p>
                Some things that will speed me up are: watching tv/Youtube, social media, notifications on my phone, working on uninteresting things, being around people for long periods of time, leaving a TV or music running in the background, or staying up to date on current world affairs.
            </p><p>
<i>Only you can figure out what speed is desirable.</i>
                I really enjoy hanging out with friends or watching a great movie just like anybody else, but the amount really matters.
                I don't want to get too sped up.
            </p><p>
<i>Slowing down is harder than speeding up.</i>
                Reading makes you smarter and running makes you healthier.
                They both can be enjoyable, but they also suck a lot of the time.
                It is work.
            </p><p>
<i>I live slowly because it makes me feel good.</i>
                We are our habits.
                Eating chocolate will make us feel good.
                Also, having a fit body will make us feel good.
                The difference is one takes a lot more effort to find.
            </p>
<small>
                
            </small>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    

        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2023-04-24</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2023-04-24"/>
            <title>
                Feeling rhymers
            </title>
            <published>2023-04-24T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2></h2>
<p>
                I love consuming great art and paying attention to what it rhymes with.
                I ask myself, what other emotions, experiences, and ideas does this cause to bubble up to my awareness?
            </p><p>
                This is fun, but it also helps me create.
                Because creating is just going the other direction.
            </p><p>
                It is being able to capture a state of being in paintings, music, text, etc.
            </p><p>
                Artists are feeling rhymers.
            </p>
<small>
                
            </small>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    

        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2023-04-23</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2023-04-23"/>
            <title>
                Perpetual companies
            </title>
            <published>2023-04-23T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2></h2>
<p>
                How much money do we, as individuals, need?
                It seems that somewhere between 1 and 10 million dollars gives you complete freedom.
                Ya know you can work, live, and spend time however you want, more or less.
                This is a very general statement, but for brevity let's assume this is true enough.
            </p><p>
                These people are content.
                They don't want anymore money.
                They live off of the 10% interest with a S&amp;P 500 ETF.
                Now they work on whatever is fun and interesting regardless of how much it will pay, if at all.
            </p><p>
                For most people, I think this is very fulfilling.
                Perhaps, one of the most fulfilling lifestyles out there.
            </p><p>
                Why not make a company like this?
            </p><p>
                Let's say you built a company.
                It gets big and has 2 billion in cash reserves.
                Lots of companies have many more billions than that.
            </p><p>
                But then as CEO you say alright we are content.
                We are slashing all but 1000 employees.
                All costs will be paid for by the 10% interest - 2 hundred million.
                Employees get a 150k salary, so that leaves 50 million for research and development costs each year.
                We no longer care about profit.
                We will only build what is fun and interesting.
            </p><p>
                Thus, we have a perpetual company.
            </p><p>
                Maybe this becomes the most creative and awesome company ever.
                Maybe culture rot would turn it into a zombie of crappy/nonexistent products.
                But if companies are in the infinite game, this would be an optimal strategy on paper right?
                Maybe giving the company an artificial death date would protect the company's health?
            </p>
<small>
                
            </small>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    

        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2023-04-22</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2023-04-22"/>
            <title>
                Smile and wave
            </title>
            <published>2023-04-22T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2></h2>
<p>
                Life is hard.
                Life can be lonely.
                But sometimes you will pass someone you know.
            </p><p>
                Often, we are too busy to acknowledge them, too caught up with my our own lives.
            </p><p>
                Instead, gather all the energy you have got, smile and wave.
                It is worth it.
            </p><p>
                The happiness it brings you and them is far greater than the small amount of effort it requires.
            </p><p>
                Life is always better with a little more love.
            </p><p>
                If I know you and I don't smile and wave, remind me :)
                I probably need a smile more than usual.
            </p>
<small>
                
            </small>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    

        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2023-04-21</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2023-04-21"/>
            <title>
                Why I don't post on social media
            </title>
            <published>2023-04-21T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2></h2>
<p>
<i>It is addictive.</i>
                Not posting ensures that I'm spending my time on what I actually want, not what the algorithm wants.
                In general, a product that thrives on addiction gets a thumbs down from me.
            </p><p>
<i>Traditional social media posts feel too self-centered, too selfish.</i>
                It feels like I'm shouting into an open room, "Look at me!"
                I don't want to waste people's time.
                I prefer to share things that could be useful.
            </p><p>
<i>Most posts aren't a real representation of who I am.</i>
                The most significant things I do aren't Instagram material.
                I don't want likes for that one insignificant weekend trip.
                That trip is not my life nor who I am.
                It almost feels like lying.
            </p><p>
<i>Posting takes me out of the moment.</i>
                When I am with someone, I really try to give them my attention.
                I never want to be thinking about what I might post later.
                I'd rather be fully there.
                Staying present is hard enough without any distractions.
                (Although, I do wish I took more pictures, but just for me.)
            </p><p>
<i>I don't want my friends to feel like an accessory.</i>
                I think my Mom uses Facebook too much, but to each their own.
                However, I won't let her post very many pictures of me because I often feel like a trophy being flaunted.
                This isn't my Mom's intention of course.
                But I don't want to do the same thing and make my friends feel like I'm spending time with them for likes.
            </p><p>
                With all of these combined, I'm happier not posting.
                Anything worth sharing can be found here, on my website.
            </p>
<small>
                
            </small>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    

        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2023-04-20</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2023-04-20"/>
            <title>
                Share your music
            </title>
            <published>2023-04-20T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2></h2>
<p>
                I used to be terrified of telling people what songs I was currently listening to.
                I was afraid of being judged.
                (A self conscious teenager? 
                No way! Haha.)
                But I think this fear is fairly common.
            </p><p>
                Music is such a powerful medium.
                Unsurprisingly, sharing that takes a lot of vulnerability.
            </p><p>        
                The first person I ever shared my music taste with became one of my closest friends.
                We liked a lot of the same stuff, and it created a really strong bond between us.
                This upside completely caught me off guard.
                They also introduced me to a lot of great music too, which was also a first.
            </p><p>
                Because of that experience, these days I am quick to share what I'm listening to.
                I've been laughed at for sharing a song, but that is alright.
                The chance to really connect with someone makes it worthwhile.
            </p><p>
                Share your music :)
            </p><p>
                P.S. What are you listening to?
            </p>
<small>
                
            </small>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    

        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2023-04-18</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2023-04-18"/>
            <title>
                AI madness
            </title>
            <published>2023-04-18T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2></h2>
<p>
            I started learning about AI about three years ago.
            It seemed like a technology that would have a large impact, and I thought it was interesting.
            Because I love the stories of Steve Jobs, Elon Musk, or any number of people that have been the face of some fantastic achievement, I thought AI might be the technology that tells my story.
            </p><p>
            Flash forward to today, AI is taking off.
            It is everywhere.
            I used to feel like I could keep up with everything that was happening.
            I probably still could today, but it would take a toll on me.
            It would throw me out of balance.
            My grip on the industry is slipping due to the growing size.
            </p><p>
            This brings new challenges.
            I get anxious as I scroll through Twitter or my AI newsletters.
            I feel like, oh great more information to drown in, more things that I don't have time to read.
            I don't really know the best way forward.
            </p><p>
            For now I'm feeling that balance and long term persistence are best.
            Mainly for two reasons.
            One, you can't force greatness.
            You can only invite it in, and the more I <i>need</i> something the faster it seems to run from me.
            Two, I think I am more likely to fail from burnout than getting washed away by the growth.
            There will always be the next thing, the new innovation.
            However, if I am too crushed to work at all, that next thing isn't available to me.
            </p><p>
            I am open to suggestions.
            </p><p>
            I do think there will come a time when I start a business, and my working hours go way up.
            But I suspect it won't throw me off balance.
            Creating something with super smart friends is the dream.
            Here I'm talking strictly about maintaining a competence on the bleeding edge of AI.
            </p>
<small>
            
            </small>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    

        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2023-04-17</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2023-04-17"/>
            <title>
                Theory vs practice
            </title>
            <published>2023-04-17T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2></h2>
<p>
            In the College of Computer Science here at Astate, there is a heavy debate about what a CS degree is for.
            Most believe it is about learning the theory behind CS.
            Others believe it is about building things with software - practice.
            </p><p>
            These two are not mutually exclusive.
            It is actually the opposite, you can't have one without the other.
            </p><p>
            We can start at either one, but we always end at the other.<br/>
<b>1) We create things because they are interesting and exciting.
            We learn what is necessary in order to create that thing.</b><br/>
<b>2) We learn theory to expand the possibilities of creation.
            We create to solidify the theory.</b>
</p><p>
            My most efficient years of education were when I bounced between both cases purely based off what I felt like doing.
            </p><p>
            I've never had a college class with <i>too much</i> practice.
            The worst classes have always leaned too heavily towards theory.
            Perhaps the issue is something else entirely: laziness.
            </p>
<small>
            
            </small>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    

        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2022-12-14</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2022-12-14"/>
            <title>
            Viewpoints
            </title>
            <published>2022-12-14T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2></h2>
<p>
            A few days ago, I was standing on the fifth floor of the Astate library, overlooking the busy parking lot below.
            Vehicles would enter only to snake up and down the rows of the completely full lot.
            </p><p>
            I couldn't help but think about how much congestion this causes everyday across the entire world.
            </p><p>
            From my viewpoint, it was obvious there were no empty spots.
            If only each driver had my birds-eye view, this could be fixed.
            </p><p>
<b>Perhaps some of our own problems could be solved with a simple change of perspective, if we were so bold.</b>
</p><p>
            A few steps back, or maybe a hundred or a thousand, could be just what we need.
            </p>
<small>
            
            </small>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    

        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2022-12-9</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2022-12-9"/>
            <title>
            When machines take over
            </title>
            <published>2022-12-09T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2></h2>
<p>What does the world look like once the machines do everything?</p>
<p>They will be the primary source of innovation and creativity.</p>
<p>You will have everything in abundance.</p>
<p>All of our problems will be solved.</p>
<p>We won't be special anymore.</p>
<p>There won't be any meaning beyond what we create ourselves.</p>
<p>You could do anything.</p>
<p><b>Do you really want all of this free time?</b></p>
<p>Could you really ask yourself, "What do I want to do?"</p>
<p>Or are you too distracted?</p>
<p>Maybe the question is too hard?</p>
<p>...</p>
<p>The world has 8 billion people that do everything.</p>
<p>Everyone else is the primary source of innovation and creativity.</p>
<p>They are providing everything in abundance for almost nothing.</p>
<p>They are solving all of the problems.</p>
<p>You aren't that special - but surly unique.</p>
<p>We don't know the meaning of life.</p>
<p>You can do anything.</p>
<p><b>Do you really want all of this free time?</b></p>
<p>Could you really ask yourself, "What do I want to do?"</p>
<p>Or are you too distracted?</p>
<p>Maybe the question is too hard?</p>
<small>
            
            </small>
<img src="../static/articles/dystopia.png"/>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    

        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2022-12-7</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2022-12-7"/>
            <title>
            That chameleon won't ever change
            </title>
            <published>2022-12-07T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2></h2>
<p>In my dream, my Dad and I were fascinated with this Chameleon.
            We thought it was so cool this animal could change colors just by touching something.</p>
<p>We wanted to test the limits its ability, so we found the most colorful thing in the room, a spiral tie dye ball.
            The ones about the size of an old school dodgeball, but much lighter and not as rubbery and thick.</p>
<p>We moved the Chameleon on top of this ball, and it starts flashing all of these different colors.
            I'm smiling as I watch.
            I think this is really cool.
            But as I look across the table, my Dad is growing extremely upset by it.</p>
<p>A few seconds later he yells out with fury, "Turn pink!"
            Frantically the animal's colors begin changing in a seemingly unnatural way.
            It looks like it is trying to force itself to become pink out of guilt, but it can only manage a few pink spots here and there.</p>
<p>My Dad yells again, but with a bit more rage, "Turn pink!"
            This time he aggressively smacks the Chameleon directly over his body and head.
            The poor Chameleon looks so ashamed as he keeps flashing colors but only with occasional pink patches.</p>
<p>To me the problem is obvious.
            On the ball there is only a small area of pink right where the spiral begins.
            He doesn't have enough pink to lay on in order to fully become that color.</p>
<p><b>The Chameleon can only create using his inputs.
            He doesn't get to choose.</b></p>
<p>Still asleep, I thought to myself, "This is a great metaphor. I should write about it."</p>
<small>
            
            </small>
<img src="../static/articles/pink.png"/>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    

        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2022-11-17</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2022-11-17"/>
            <title>
            Stop caring about your degree: How I look at college
            </title>
            <published>2022-11-17T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2></h2>
<p>It is common to think of college as a ticket that guarantees a stable uninteresting job allowing you to buy stuff.
            Supposedly, this will make you happy.</p>
<p>I hate this so much.</p>
<p>I think the previous generations' storage units full of crap didn't make them happy.
            The security they were promised is becoming less secure every day.
            More importantly, they traded their mission for their employer's greed, and that shit is fatal.</p>
<p>If that is what a degree gets you, I don't want it.</p>
<p>From that perspective, <i>my degree</i> is worthless.
            However, my <i>college years</i> are not.</p>
<p>I'm not against working for someone.
            There are plenty of really desirable companies out there.
            Even if they don't share my mission, I can't help but applaud their's.</p>
<p>All of these great companies all ask the same thing to job applicants.
            <b>What problems have you solved, what things have you built, or what teams have you led?</b>
            But only having a college degree leaves you with one answer: I'm sorry for wasting your time.</p>
<p>These questions offer fantastic guidance though.
            I try to spend as much effort and time on those three things as possible.</p>
<p>To be clear, this isn't so I can get a job at these companies.
            Really, it is all about my mission.
            Those questions just further prove that the ability to pursue it is super valuable.
            And no wonder.</p>
<p>It is a chance to be useful, connect, and touch the hearts of people around me today.<br/>
            It is making something that I love (and hopefully others too.)<br/>
            It is fixing things that are ugly and broken.<br/></p>
<p>To me this is obviously so much more important than my degree.
            I often trade extra time chasing my mission for worse grades.
            I do good enough to pass and keep my scholarships, but I treat my classes as introductions to new ideas - not vital information for the test.</p>
<p>The world barley cares about my degree, and so do I.</p>
<small>
            
            </small>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    

        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2022-10-24</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2022-10-24"/>
            <title>
            Be selfish to win
            </title>
            <published>2022-10-24T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2></h2>
<p>
                Only do stuff that benefits you.
                Don't treat others with respect or kindness.
                Ask but never give.
                If it doesn't help you, why bother?
            </p>
<p>
                This is obviously a bad long term strategy.
            </p>
<p>
                I wouldn't call this selfishness.
                It's actually just being dumb.
            </p>
<p>
<b><i>In order to be truly selfish, we have to be selfless.</i></b>
</p>
<p>
                Selfishness and selflessness are two sides of the same coin.
                You don't get one without the other.
            </p>
<p>
                To maximize our own profit and pleasure, we should maximize the problems we solve for others.
            </p>
<p>
<b><i>Help the most people = Reap the most benefits</i></b>
</p>
<p>
                However, you can't help lots of people without helping one.
                So start helping those around you first.
                Love and respect go a long way.
                Gifts are great desert.
            </p>
<p>
                So go on and be selfish... err, I mean selfless ;)
            </p>
<small>
            
            </small>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    

        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2022-10-16</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2022-10-16"/>
            <title>
            Pesky legacy necessity
            </title>
            <published>2022-10-16T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2></h2>
<p>
            Legacy - measured by making things better - is a noble aspiration.
            But the process is tricky.
            </p>
<p>
<i>If you are desperate to leave a legacy, you lose.</i>
</p>
<p>
            The world seems to hate needy things.
            </p>
<p>
            People like this always feel inauthentic - always peddling themselves.
            Even their best intentions seem inconsiderate.
            </p>
<p>
            Contentment makes you more open to smaller humbler projects.
            Finding something useful and good to do is easy, but legacy necessity will make these things feel too insignificant to invest in.
            </p>
<p>
            Besides, nobody can plan the next path to greatness anyways.
            </p>
<p>
            Make it easier on yourself and let go of the need to leave a legacy.
            </p>
<small>
            
            </small>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    

        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2022-06-11</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2022-06-11"/>
            <title>	
            An unusual message for people who want to change the world
            </title>
            <published>2022-06-11T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2></h2>
<p>
                If you want to change the world, you probably feel aimless. You have no clear path at all, but despite the unknown, you still feel compelled to do something big. That is okay, and it is the only way to reliably achieve great things.
            </p>
<p>
                These ideas come from <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Why-Greatness-Cannot-Planned-Objective/dp/3319155237" target="_blank">"Why Greatness Cannot Be Planned"</a>, so this is very condensed. I encourage you to read the whole book, but I introduce the two main concepts from the book in this article.
            </p>
<ul>
<li>
                    When trying to achieve large goals such as changing the world, <i><b>objectives don't work.</b></i>
</li>
<li>
                    Instead of objectives, we should chase <i><b>interesting and novel</b></i> ideas.
                </li>
</ul>
<h2>
                Objectives are out
            </h2>
<p>
                Imagine that youre given an enormous petri dish the size of Earth. On this petri dish are single-celled organisms that are equivalent to the very first living cells on Earth, from which all other life eventually evolved. Your <i><b>objective</b></i> is to evolve organisms with human-level intelligence by selecting which organisms should reproduce. The basic idea is to replace natural selection with your own decisions about who gets to reproduce. Of course, it may sound difficult, but to make the problem easier you are allowed four billion years to finish.
            </p>
<p>
                The great thing about this experiment is that we know its possible because those very single-celled organisms did evolve over billions of years into human beings. The main challenge is just to be a good breeder because selecting which organisms will reproduce is ultimately nothing more than animal breeding. All you need to do is select parents to mate that are increasingly human-like and voil, you are done before you know it.
            </p>
<p>
                So what should be your strategy to breed single-celled organisms all the way to human-level intelligence? Wed like to suggest a clear-headed approach that gets right to the heart of the matter: You can administer intelligence tests to the single-celled organisms! Then all you need to do is pick the ones that score highest to be the parents of the next generation. Soon enough, were on our way to a real Einstein, right?
            </p>
<p>
                Or maybe not. Clearly, this strategy is deeply flawed. If you really administered IQ tests to single-celled organisms, you would be lucky if they even survived, let alone evolved intelligence of any sort. But why wouldnt something like that work? After all, it respects the general principle that we measure progress towards our goals by comparing where we are to where we want to be. But that principle is increasingly suspicious, as this thought experiment exposes once again.
            </p>
<p>
                The problem is that the <i><b>stepping stones</b></i> to intelligence do not resemble intelligence at all. Put another way, human-level intelligence is a deceptive <i><b>objective</b></i> for evolution. Once again, deception rears its confusing and misdirecting head. Rather than increasing intelligence, the stepping stones that lead from single-celled organisms to humans include such unrelated innovations as multicellularity and bilateral symmetry. Millions of years ago our ancestor was a flatworm. It would not score any accolades for its intellect, but its one great achievement was bilateral symmetry. Who would ever think that bilateral symmetry is essential to writing poetry? But it was an essential stepping stone on the road to Shakespeare. The problem with the intelligence test approach is that it entirely fails to detect such monumentally important discoveries. Instead it wastes precious effort measuring a property that will not come into play in any important way until eons in the future.
            </p>
<p>
                That may seem obvious because subjecting a cell to an IQ test (or any intelligence test) is unquestionably ridiculous. But the fact that it is ridiculous is exactly the point, and is why this experiment should ring alarm bells for anyone who still believes in the myth of the objective. Is it any less ridiculous to try to achieve any far-off, ambitious objective by measuring how close it is to our best candidate so far? What this thought experiment exposes is that the traditional approach to achievement, driven by and informed by objectives, can lead to genuinely ridiculous behavior. But ridiculous or not, the assumption that objectives should drive achievement dominates our culture and our everyday lives.
            </p>
<p>
                Evolution in nature is a <i><b>stepping-stone</b></i> collector. These stepping stones are collected not because they may lead to some far off primary objective, some ultimate uber-organism towards which all of life is directed, but because they are well-adapted in their own right. Each organism on the path to humans reproduced because it was successful in its own niche at its own time.
            </p>
<h2>
                Chase the interesting and novel
            </h2>
<p>
                Novelty can often act as a <i><b>stepping stone</b></i> detector because anything novel is a potential stepping stone to something even more novel. In other words, novelty is a rough shortcut for identifying interestingness: Interesting ideas are those that open up new possibilities. And while it might sound wishy-washy to go looking for interesting things, interestingness is a surprisingly deep and important concept.
            </p>
<p>
                The important point is that novelty (and interestingness) can compound over time by continually making new things possible. So instead of seeking a final objective, by looking for novelty the reward is an endless chain of stepping stones branching out into the future as novelty leads to further novelty. Rather than thinking of the future as a destination, it becomes a road, a path of undefined potential. Evolution in nature and human innovation are ratcheting processes that build stepping stone upon stepping stone, branching and diverging ever outward to everywhere and nowhere in particular.
            </p>
<p>
                But there might still seem to be a problem. Chasing novelty suggests a kind of aimless uncertainty. How do we know where were going? But thats exactly the point. The greatest processes of innovation work precisely because they are not trying to go anywhere in particular. In this sense, weve abandoned the false security of the objective to embrace the wild possibility of the unknown. Of course, theres still reason for concern. Such a search for novelty still feels unanchored and perhaps even almost random. Would it not simply chart a course from one fleeting novelty to another? Why should we believe that such a process has any meaning to it?
            </p>
<p>
                Because we can look to the past and see it works. I chose the natural selection example because I think almost everyone is familiar with the concept, but these ideas can be seen in all innovation whether it be the creation of the computer or the airplane... both of which are included in the actual book. Sure there is still the possibility that you spend your entire life working and never achieve greatness, but if you are reading this, you are probably the type of person that is going to forge ahead anyways. That fear will always be there, but now you can stop being so anxious about not having a clear and detailed plan. Chase the interesting and the novel if you want to change the world.
            </p>
<p>
<b>Greatness is possible if you are willing to stop demanding what that greatness should be.</b>
</p>
<h2>
                So what am I doing?
            </h2>
<p>
                I am trying my best to push humanity forward by letting go of objectives and pursing novel things that are interesting to me. 
            </p>
<p>
                Even if all of this is not true, what else would I do with my life? I'm open to better answers, but so far this is the best one I've found.
            </p>
<p>
                So what interests you? <a href="mailto:wilderchange@gmail.com">Email me.</a>
</p>
<small>
                
            </small>
<hr/>
<small>
                This concept was introduced to me in the book <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Why-Greatness-Cannot-Planned-Objective/dp/3319155237" target="_blank">Greatness Cannot Be Planned</a>, and in fact most of this text is directly from the book.
                I highly encourage you read it if you found this interesting but lacking further detail.
            </small>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    

        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2022-05-25</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2022-05-25"/>
            <title>	
                Tell Great Stories
            </title>
            <published>2022-05-25T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2></h2>
<p>
                Great stories inspire. Great stories teach. Great stories move people.
            </p>
<p>
                When David Goggins is asked, "What is your greatest fear?" He could answer, "My greatest fear is not living up to my fullest potential."
            </p>
<p>
                But Goggins is a master story teller. Here is his response.
            </p>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FbgTPbaku8s?start=13" title="YouTube video player" width="560"></iframe>
<small>
                
            </small>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    

        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2023-04-19</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2023-04-19"/>
            <title>
                College sucks but people don't
            </title>
            <published>2023-04-19T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2></h2>
<p>
            Spend 10 minutes after your college classes talking to your professors and classmates.
            This has accounted for 80% of my degree's value.
            </p><p>
            The opportunities, friends, and sense of community that results from this small amount of time is kind of wild.
            </p><p>
            When the professor is teaching you can't connect with anyone.
            So after class, I often take 10 minutes or so just to talk.
            I'm never trying to use people.
            I'm just a curious guy in a room with people who are interested in similar things as me.
            </p><p>
            College may be inefficient, but I would probably never meet these people on my own.
            </p>
<small>
            
            </small>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    

        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2022-03-25</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2022-03-25"/>
            <title>
            The Most Important Question
            </title>
            <published>2022-03-25T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2></h2>
<p>
            What would you do if you could have anything? If you could go anywhere? If you were completely free of all obligation and constraint? What would you do?
            </p>
<p>
            This is the most important question.
            </p>
<p>
            We should all ask ourselves this on a regular basis.
            </p>
<small>
                
            </small>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    

        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2022-03-24</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2022-03-24"/>
            <title>
            Adaptomaniac
        </title>
            <published>2022-03-24T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2></h2>
<blockquote>
<p>
<b>noun</b>
</p>
<p>
        They have an insatiable curiosity and have experimented with a little bit of everything. When you look at their resume, you see a broad range of experience in terms of industry, technologies, and roles.
        </p>
<p>
        Perhaps the strongest sign of an adaptomaniac is not the experience they already have but the willingness to take on any new experience. 
        </p>
<p>
        If you hear a developer say "Oh, no, I'm not a front end guy" or cringe at the thought of having to learn a new programming language for their next project, they are probably not an adaptomaniac.
        </p>
<p>
        Real adaptomaniacs love to learn new things regardless of the problem domain and whether they have any experience in it.
        </p>
</blockquote>
<small>
            
        </small>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    

        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2022-03-16</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2022-03-16"/>
            <title>
        The Best Introductory Coding Course. Period.
        </title>
            <published>2022-03-16T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2></h2>
<p>
        Like me, many years ago, I assume your idea of a programmer is this mystical creature that is only seen in broad daylight on rare occasions. You have a vague idea of what "coding" entails, but for some crazy reason - I was interested in Ai - you have decided that you want to learn how to code.
        </p>
<p>
        Take Harvard's free online course, CS50x: Introduction to CS.
        </p>
<p>
        I took this is high school, and it was and is better than my entry level CS classes at my current college!
        </p>
<p>
        You will get the perfect blend of depth and breadth in this entry level course. Once you finish CS50x, they actually have three follow up courses CS50w (websites), CS50ai (Ai), and CS50g (games). I have only taken the two former classes, but I have no doubt the latter is just as fantastic.
        </p>
<p>
        I can't express my gratitude and excitement enough. David Malan, Brain Yu, and Doug Llyod are all fantastic teachers, and their style and enthusiasm should be imitated by professors around the globe.
        </p>
<p>
        If you guys see this... Thank You.
        </p>
<small>
            
        </small>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    

        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2022-03-14</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2022-03-14"/>
            <title>
            Stop Killing Your Ideas: Jot Them Down
            </title>
            <published>2022-03-14T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2></h2>
<p>
            If you are someone who creates things it is imperative that you jot fleeting ideas down.
            </p>
<p><b>
            Ideas don't come out fully formed.
            </b></p>
<p>
            By jotting down any thought that is even vaguely interesting, you allow it to grow. Just trying to remember it is deliberately killing your ideas of out laziness.            </p>
<p>
            Once the idea is safely and briefly recorded, your mind is free to be creative and follow other long rabbit holes without worry.
            </p>
<p>
            You will be amazed at just how creative you can be, if only you would stop killing your ideas.
            </p>
<small>
                
            </small>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    

        <entry>
            <id>https://bloge.li/articles/2022-03-12</id>
            <link href="https://bloge.li/articles/2022-03-12"/>
            <title>	
            Be A Pirate: Resumes And Why I Hate Them
            </title>
            <published>2022-03-12T00:00:00Z</published>
            <content type="html">
                <section id="article">
<h2></h2>
<p>
            Resumes and other short forms of displaying "achievement" will be the death of me.
            </p>
<p>
            I hate trying to put a lifetime on a sheet of paper, and I shouldn't have to. Resumes shouldn't be a list of checkboxes that you tick off because this leads to people putting all kinds of fugazi type stuff on there. Things that don't really matter or don't exist at all. Just filler.
            </p>
<blockquote>
<i>
            "Fugayzi, fugazi. It's a whazy. It's a woozie. It's fairy dust. It doesn't exist. It's never landed. It is no matter. It's not on the elemental chart. It's not fucking real."
            </i>
<br/>
            - Matthew McConaughey in the Wolf of Wall Street
            </blockquote>
<p>
            The problem lies in how the majority of people evaluate them, not the resume itself.
            </p>
<p>
            The solution is a simple one. Be a pirate. Look for shiny things.
            </p>
<p>
            Look for one really awesome thing on the resume. A singular thing that makes you think wow, this is awesome, should be enough to start the interview process.
            </p>
<p>
            If everyone hired this way, then writing a resume would be way easier too! All you would do is list the bare essentials and add all the things that you consider to be "shiny".
            </p>
<small>
                
            </small>
</section>
            </content>
        </entry>
    
</feed>